David M. Stowe Papers
Yale University Divinity School Library
David M. Stowe Papers
1806-2003
1949-1999
RG 156
Yale University Divinity School Library
101
(244 boxes)
Correspondence, sermons, lectures, writings, reports, slides, and collected material document the life and work of David M. Stowe, who was a top level executive for the American Board of Commissioners for Foreign Missions, the United Church Board for World Ministries, and the National Council of Church Division of Overseas Ministries. The collection includes extensive documentation of the history of the ABCFM and UCBWM that Stowe compiled in preparation for writing a history of the Boards.
Stowe, David M.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Virginia Ware Stowe, 2003-2008
Conditions Governing Access
Open to qualified researchers.
Arrangement
Series I. Correspondence, 1940s-1999
Series II. Sermons, Lectures, Talks by DMS, 1942-1999
Series III. Writings of DMS, 1940-2001
Series IV. Drafts, Notes,Sources for Proposed Board History, 1812-1980s
Series V. Resource Files: ABCFM/UCBWM Documents, 1806-1996
Series VI. Resource Files: ABCFM/UCBWM Geographical / Topical Files, 1810-2003
Series VII. DMS "Working Files", 1950s-1990s
Series VIII. DMS Activities: Church and Ecumenical, 1954-1999
Series IX: DMS Activities: Teaching and Research, 1949-1990s
Series X. Personal Items and Memorabilia, 1911-2000
Series XI. Addendum - 2011, 1881-2001
Biographical / Historical
Chronology of David M. Stowe
1919 Mar 30 David Metz Stowe was born in Council Bluffs, Iowa
1940 After attending Midland Lutheran College for two years, DMS transferred to the from University of California at Los Angeles and graduated with highest honors. Phi Beta Kappa 1943 B.D., Pacific School of Religion, Berkeley, CA
1943 Married Virginia Ware (Children: Nancy, Elizabeth, Priscilla, David)
1943-1945 Ordained; served as campus minister at First Congregational Church, a United Church congregation in Berkeley
1945-1947 Under appointment as missionaries of the American Board of Commissioners for Foreign Missions, DMS and VWS studied Chinese language and culture at Yale University Institute of Far Eastern Languages
1947 Left for China; additional study at Chinese Language School in Peking
1948 Assigned to general evangelistic work in Tientsin
1949-1950 Assigned to faculty of Yenching University in Peking. DMS and VWS taught freshman English and DMS taught Western philosophy and New Testament in the School of Religion
1950 Jun Forced to leave China because of outbreak of Korean War
1951-1953 Served as Associate Minister of the First Congregational Church in Berkeley while attending Pacific Sschool of Religion
1953 Received Th.D. degree from Pacific School of Religion
1953-1956 Served as Chaplain and professor of religion at Carleton College, Northfield, MN
1956 Called to the national headquarters of the American Board of Commissioners for Foreign Missions (ABCFM) in Boston to serve as its educational secretary
1957-1963 General Secretary for Interpretation and Personnel of the newly formed United Church Board for World Ministries (UCBWM) following merger of Congregational Christian Churches and Evangelical and Reformed Church to form the United Church of Christ (UCC); also served as adjunct professor at Andover-Newton Theological School during this period
1962-1963 On special assignment in Beirut, Lebanon, to teach in the Near East School of Theology. Also visited missions and participated in conferences in Asia, Africa and the Middle East
1963-1965 Returned to U.S. to serve as Executive Secretary of the Division of Foreign Missions of the National Council of Churches of Christ in the U.S.A. (NCCCUSA)
1965-1970 Associate General Secretary of the NCCCUSA and director of the Division of Overseas Ministries
1966 Honorary doctorate from Pacific School of Religion
1970-1985 Served as Executive Vice President of the United Church Board for World Ministries
1985-1999 In the years following his retirement from the UCBWM, DMS served as volunteer archivist and historian for the UCBWM, adjunct lecturer in missions at Andover Newton, Theological Seminary, adjunct professor at Pacific School of Religion (1985-1986), secretary-treasurer of the Eastern Fellowship,American Society of Missiology, officer of the World Commission on Religion and Peace, and tour leader for UCC tours to China.
2000 Jan 10 Died in Englewood, NJ
Scope and Contents
The papers of David M. Stowe are valuable both for their biographical documentation and for the extensive documentation they contain related to the history of the American Board of Commissioners for Foreign Missions and United Church Board for World Ministries. Throughout his long career as a China missionary, professor, and mission executive, David Stowe was an acute observer and wise analyst of the many issues facing the Christian enterprise in the second half of the twentieth century. Stowe was both a theologian and an historian. His extensive writings theological and missions-related issues and his participation in many important meetings and events are well documented in this collection. A large portion of the collection consists of the material Stowe wrote and gathered in preparation for writing a comprehensive history of the ABCFM and UCBWM. Stowe never completed this work but has left behind a well-organized and extensive gathering of source materials that will be of use to researchers on many topics.
Missions -- China; Missionaries; Stowe, David M.; American Board of Commissioners for Foreign Missions; United Church Board for World Ministries
- Correspondence, 1940s-1999; Series I
  Scope and Contents
  This series is comprised of primarily personal correspondence. The family letters and circular letters begin with documentation of the Stowes' work as missionaries in China and provide a good overview of their activities in various locations and positions. Correspondence from the later years documents Stowe's wide circle of friends and colleagues and his work in providing and gathering information about the ABCFM and UCBWM. A set of microfilm containing Stowe's correspondence as Executive Vice President of the UCBWM, 1970-1985, completes the series. See additional correspondence in Series XI, Addendum.
  - Family personal correspondence
    - Incl. to David Stowe (DMS) parents (Mr. and Mrs. E. L. Stowe), to Ruth from Virginia Stowe (VWS), 1940s-1950s (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - To DMS parents, 1960-1963 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - To DMS parents, Jim, Nancy (VWS sister), extended family, DMS from VWS, the Wares, Gene and Faye Stowe, to VWS and children from DMS, 1964-1965 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - To Nancy, to VWS and children from DMS, Jo, extended family, Liz, to DMS from Sally, VWS, DMS parents, Aunt Edith, Ruth, 1966-1967 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - To extended family, Liz, DMS family (from Gene and Faye), Gene and Faye, Harold and Anne, Tom, the Wares, Nan, Gram, 1968-1970 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - To extended family, Jo and John, VWS and children from DMS), DMS parents, to DMS family from Edwin and Florence Hambrick, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - To DMS family from Constance, VWS, DMS parents, Tom and Nan, Harold and Anne, extended family, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - To Constance from VWS and DMS, the Wares, Pris, extended family, 1975-1977 (Box 1, Folder 8-9)
    - To extended family, Nancy and Tom, Elizabeth, Priscilla, the Wares, Ed and Florence, Constance, 1978-1979 (Box 1, Folder 10-11)
    - To Florence Stowe and Anne Ware, Constance, Dr. Avery Post and Rev. John Bracke, Louise, the Hambrick-Stowes, extended family, 1980-1981 (Box 1, Folder 12-13)
    - To extended family, Gene and Faye, Tom and Nan, the Inuis, Pris, 1982-1983 (Box 1, Folder 14-15)
    - To extended family, Tinker, Anne, "daughters," "Mother"; Frank and Beulah Mae, 1984-1985 (Box 1, Folder 16-17)
    - To extended family, Tom and Nan, David Stowe (from Gayla), 1986-1989 (Box 1, Folder 18-20)
    - To VWS and DMS (from Gene and Faye), Anne, Clarice and Kyle, Dorothy, Tom and Chuck, 1991-1990 (Box 2, Folder 21-23)
    - To extended family, VWS and DMS from Gene and Faye, Kit and Paul, Kyle and Clarice, "Mother" and Bud, Grandma Ware, 1992 (Box 2, Folder 24-25)
    - To extended family, VWS and DMS from Joan, Chuck, Larry and Kit; Frank, extended family, Hank and BJ, VWS and DMS from Gene and Faye, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 26-27)
    - To extended family, Hank and BJ; Bud and Joan, Elizabeth; to Anne, "international family," Dave and Linda, Laura, Pris, the Westons, 1994-1996 (Box 2, Folder 28-30)
    - To extended family, Faye and Gene, Frank and Beulah, Frank, Laura and Elizabeth, Dave and Laura, DMSfrom Jane Spragg, Nancy and family, 1997 (Box 2, Folder 31)
    - To Gene and Faye, Elizabeth, extended family, Dave and Linda, "E & E," Peg, Henry and Hattie, DMS from Ray Gibson, Nancy, 1998 (Box 2, Folder 32)
    - To extended family, Joan and Bud, Connie, "D & L" (Dave and Linda), Nan, Jim, Elizabeth Hambrick-Stowe, Tazo, Tom and Nancy, "C & E," VWS and DMS from Thomas Hambrick- Stowe, Tazo, Priscilla, 1999 (Box 2, Folder 33)
    - To VWS and DMS from Gene and Faye, Bud and Joan, Tom and Chuck, "Mom," Flo, Mom and Bud, ), extended family, "Mom," "Dad," DMS from VWS, Harold and Anne (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Stowe circular letters
    - Letter from China (1947); dated Christmas letters (1946, 1950, 1956, 1965, 1986, 1991, 1992), undated Christmas letters (Carleton College, Dwight St. - New Haven), "Reflections on Mission in a Land Rich in Religions", 1946-1992, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Pre-1990s personal correspondence
    - Barlow, Edward J.; Battaglia, Victor; Chang Yun-sheng, aka Warren Chang; Chen Ji-wen; Chen, Lucy and Chao, Timothy and Walter; Dewar, Mary; Donovan, Hedley; Fisher, Edwin O. (enclosure: Yang letter), pre-1990s (Box 3, Folder 36)
    - Hausske, Albert C.; Hemingway, Isabel "Izzy"; Huo Tongchung; Jiang Mingtao; Kelly, John D; Li Ding-Jiu; Lin Tao; Liu Ching-fen; Lo Chao-jung; Lou Qing Ogui; Mayor and Council of Tenafly; McGee, Frank (c/o The Today Show); Gregory, Paul R.; Mo Riexi;Nixon, Richard, pre-1990s (Box 3, Folder 37-40)
    - Reed, Alice; Schutz, Roger; Scott, Agnes; Searles, W.H.; Bishop Shen; Shiao Jia-Chih; Studley, Ellen; Sun Shu-chen; Swaner, John; Bishop K.H. Ting; Wang Tsun-Hua; Wang You; Wang Zhao Gwang; Wei Chuan-chu; White, Kaye; Williams, Mell; Wong Li Gong (Robert), pre-1990s (Box 3, Folder 41-43)
    - Xu Yan; Yang An-ding (An-ting); Yang Chung-hou; Yang Chung-hou; Zhu Chang-jun; First Names Only, pre-1990s (Box 3, Folder 44-47)
  - 1980s personal correspondence
    - B-C; Clasper, Paul; Cormons, Matt; Coryell, Dorothea, 1985-1989 (Box 173, Folder 1-5)
    - D-H; Hemingway, Isabel; Henderson, Larry and Ki, 1985-1989 (Box 173, Folder 6-12)
    - I-K; Kaneda, Yoshikuni; Keithahn, Richard, 1985-1988 (Box 173, Folder 13-16)
    - L-M; Libbey, Scott, 1986-1989 (Box 173, Folder 17-18)
    - M-N; Mickey, Robert; Otto, George Dr, 1984-1989 (Box 174, Folder 19-22)
    - P-R; Palmerlee, Charles and Joy; Post, Avery and Peg; Quick, Bernard; Record, The; Rooks, Charles Shelby, 1984-1989 (Box 174, Folder 23-29)
    - S-Z; Smith, Dalton and Kitty; First names only, 1985-1989 (Box 174, Folder 30-37)
  - 1990s personal correspondence
    - Abbott, J.; Adams, Gerald; Akaka, Rev. Abraham; Aki, George; Alward, Robert S.; Andrews, Peggy; "Anya"; Aramco World, 1990s (Box 3, Folder 48)
    - Bailey, Martin and Betty; Baker, Marion; Ball, Bob and Cindy; Barber, George; Ballon, Pat; Barbour, Ian and Pam; Batten, Cindy; Bennett, Carl; Beck, Elizabeth; Becker, Carl and Gladys; Bernabeo, Paul; The Bergen-Record; Berry, Dorothy, 1990s (Box 3, Folder 49)
    - Bielecki, Marek W.; Birchard, Roy; Bishop, Eunice; Blackburn, Wayne and Helen; Blakney, Charles; Blemker, Margaret (Peg); Boardman, Jean and Howard, 1990s (Box 3, Folder 50)
    - Braun, Richard; Brown, G. Thompson; Brunger, Grace; Brown, Charles and Nadine; Brown, Marguerite; Burns, Charles L.; Burrows, Williams; Byerly, Don, 1990s (Box 3, Folder 51)
    - Calavan, Frances; Campbell, Joan; Capek, Milic; Chain, Beverly; Chapman, Audrey; Chong, Elly; Christian Century; Christofersen, Howard; Clark, Betty; Clark, Winnie; Clayton, Paul; Clinton, Bill, 1990s (Box 3, Folder 52)
    - Coates, Ken and Barbara; Colson, Charles; Conmans, Matt; Copeland, John; Corr, Phillip; Coryell, Dorothea Smith; Cribbs (?), Art; Crockett, Larrimore; Crothers, James M.; Crozier, Rev. J. P.; Culver, Marybeth, 1990s (Box 3, Folder 53)
    - Dean, David and Jean; Devenish, Philip; DeVries, Gretchen; Dickinson, Dorothy M.; Diehl, Henry; Donaldson, J. Franklin; Downey, Bill and Sabine, 1990s (Box 4, Folder 54)
    - Drummond, Richard; Du, Philip H.; Duck, Ruth, 1990s (Box 4, Folder 55)
    - Edwards, Robert; Engberg, J.; Espy, Cleo; Everett, Bill; Eymann, Harold and Gladys, 1990s (Box 4, Folder 56)
    - Fackre, Gabriel; Fairfield, J; Fantes, Pim; Felible, Roma and John; Ferré, Nels F.S., 1990s (Box 4, Folder 57)
    - ﻿Focht, Paul (and Al and Dorris?); Forsyth, Margret Campbell; Fothergill, Don; Frost, Dorothy, ﻿1990s (Box 4, Folder 58)
    - Gaylord, Edward; Gallup, Padmasani and David; Galt, Ralph; Gibson, Ray; Gilg, Audrey; Gilley, Lawrence C.; Glenn, Karen and Colin, 1990s (Box 4, Folder 59)
    - Goodpasture, Ken; Goodspeed, Kate; Grant, Ida Madeline; Gray, Helen; Greenhaw, David; Gregory, Paul and Kit; Guzzo, Dorothy, 1990s (Box 4, Folder 60)
    - Hackett, Beth and Arnold; Weil-Hackett, Peter and Susan; Hallstram, Sybil; Hamerton-Kelly, Robert; Hamilton, Jim; Hansen, Harriett; Haskins, Stuart C.; Hastie, Ed, 1990s (Box 4, Folder 61)
    - Hayden, Henry and Betty Jane (aka Hank and BJ); Heller, Rita; Heim, Melissa; Hein, Chuck and Gaby; Heininger, Ed; Hemingway, Isabel; Henderson, Larry and Ki; Herald of Holiness, Editor; Hirano, David, 1990s (Box 4, Folder 62-63)
    - Hlatshwayo; Hoffman, Dan C.; Holladay, Bill; Horvath, Ted; Hu, Izzy; Hulteen, William; Hunter, Annarae; Hutchison, Frank; Hway, 1990s (Box 4, Folder 64-65)
    - Ideim, Melissa; Inbanathan, S. Stephen R.; Inui, Frank and Beulah; Jack, Homer A.; Jamieson, David and Betty; Jackson, Dorothy; Jacobs, Tom; Jickling, Dave and Cynthia; Johns, David and Ginny; Jones, Alfred; Joseph, Chinnaraj, 1990s (Box 4, Folder 66-67)
    - Kaina, William and Sandy; Kaneda, Yoshikuni; Keach, Rev. Stanley; Keeler, Bill and Margaret; Kelly, William; Kitagawa, Fujiko; Krass, Al; Kuether, Gustav H., 1990s (Box 4, Folder 68-69)
    - Laun, ?; Lavely, Josephine; Leekpai, Chuan; Litwak, Robert S.; Lowe, John; MacInnis, Don; Mackenzie, Helen; Markham, Robin and Fran; Marks, Nancy; Maslanek, Rita; Matthews, Alden, 1990s (Box 4, Folder 70-71)
    - McKinney, Bill; McMillan, Joseph; Maxfield, Christy Ann Ranck and Charles A.; Mayers, Eugene; Meyer, Sylvia and Hans; Meyer, Wim; Midgley, Bob and Lois; Miller, Fern and Bill; Miller, Janice; Minear, Gladys, 1990 (Box 4, Folder 72)
    - Moffett, Eileen and Sam; Mook, Telfer and Jane; Moscovitz, Ann A.; Mulholland, Kenneth B.; Myrick, Judith and Allen; M., Margaret; Nakagawa (Nippon Christian Academy); Nelson, Edith; Nelson, Jim, 1990s (Box 5, Folder 73-74)
    - Nichols, Sue; Norberg, Richard; Nute, William; Orander, Donald M.; Otterness, Omar; Patten, Kay; Pavich Family Farms; Petersen, Linda and Mike, et. al.; Phi Beta Kappa; Phillips, Clifton; Plate, Naomi, 1990s (Box 5, Folder 75-77)
    - Poirier, Penny (and Tim Smith); Poitras, Edward; Polk, Robert; Porter, Robert; Post, Avery and Peg; Potter Family; Pratt, Anne; Pray, Lawrence M.; Purdy, Eloise; Quilici, Janet; Rand, Peter; Register, Fred P.; Riesz, Dick and Joyce; Riggs, Ed, 1990s (Box 5, Folder 78-79)
    - Robbins; Rooney, Sandra; Ruhama; Roukema, Marge; Said, Lt. General Ali; Sasaki, Takashi and Noriko; Satterthwaite, Adaline Pendleton; Schellhase, Richard and Kay; Schomer, Howard and Elise; Schomer, Karine, 1990s (Box 5, Folder 80-82)
    - Scott, Waldron; Shepard, Fred and Mary Alice; Sherman, Gordon and Cy; Sherman, Margot; Sherry, Paul A.; Smucker, Jim; Soule, ?; Sovik, Arne; Stackhouse, Max; Stetson, Kirk and Bunni; Stiers, Thomas; Stinehelfer, Jeffrey; Stinson, Jerry; Stowe, Virginia; Strehen, Bob, 1990s (Box 5, Folder 83-84)
    - Takeda, Michiko; Takenaka, Masako; Tankersley, Betty and Larry; Tenafly Historic Preservation Commission; Tenafly Public Schools; Terpstra, Chet and Marge, 1990s (Box 5, Folder 85)
    - Thelin, Bob and Nelda; Thomas, Norman; Thurber, Connie and Newton and Lucius; Tong, Curtis; Utter, Jeff; Van Meter, Jo; Wall, David R.; Wangchuck, King Jigme Singye; Woodward, C.H., 1990s (Box 5, Folder 86-87)
    - First Names Only; Unidentified, 1990s (Box 5, Folder 88-91)
  - 1990s correspondence with Chinese colleagues and friends
    - Liu Ching-fen, Dr. Ma Ming-kuang; Bishop Ting, Wang Zhao-guang, Xu Yan and Feng Jiang, 1990s (Box 5, Folder 92-93)
    - Xu Yan and Feng-Jian; Yang Chung Hou, 1990s (Box 5, Folder 94-95)
    - First Names Only, "Cindy and Bob", 1990s (Box 5, Folder 96)
  - Professional correspondence
    - Microfilm of DMS correspondence as Executive Vice President of the UCBWM, 1970-1984 (Box 216)
- Sermons, Lectures, Talks by DMS, 1942-1999; Series II
  The extent and variety of speaking engagements by Stowe documented in this series provide good documentation of his personal beliefs and views on mission policy.
  - Sermons
    - Early sermons
      - Seminary Sermons incl: "The Person I hope to Become"; " I Believe"; and "Insight and Reality", 1940s (Box 6, Folder 1)
      - Pre-China Sermon Outlines incl: "Why Some Hate Christmas"; "Two Questions about Missions"; "Hope"; "When God Died"; and "Witness to the Truth", 1940s (Box 6, Folder 2)
      - Sermons and Sermon Outlines incl: "Problem of Evil"; "Lent"; "Life of Prayer"; and "Beauty in Common Place", 1940s- 1943 (Box 6, Folder 3)
      - Sermons Vol. I incl: "This New Age of Fear"; "The Uses of Dying"; "For Sinners Only"; "The Cross as Power"; and "For Many...For You", 1942-1945 (Box 6, Folder 4-5)
      - Misc. Prayers, Sermons, Notes: Late 1940s-Early 1950s Incl: "God is the Eternal"; "Er-Tung Gusher"; "Faculty Prayer Meeting Dec. 1949"; "I Believe in God"; and "When God Laughs", 1940s-1950s (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Radio Sermons-Berkeley
      - "A Royal Road to Romance" and "Whose War Is It?", 1944,1945 (Box 6, Folder 7)
      - Incl: "Emmaus: The Greatest Story of Easter Evening"; "Hungry for a King"; "Our Surprising Christianity"; "Deep Calling Unto Deep"; and "Three Christmases in China", 1951 (Box 6, Folder 8)
      - Incl: "Clearing the Ground"; "Jonah Speaks Today"; "The Ministry of Things"; "Church Spires"; and "The Meaning of Thanksgiving", 1952 (Box 6, Folder 9)
      - Incl: "They Don't Like Jesus"; "Abundant Life"; and "The Lure of Perfection"; Incl: "Loneliness"; "Through Science to God"; "A Death to be Envied"; and "The Wise Man and the Dragon", 1953, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 10-11)
    - Non-Berkeley Radio and Television Sermons
      - Sermons: "It May be Better than You Think" [Radio], "What Faith Is" [CBS Church of the Air], "World Missions--Heritage and Horizons [WTMJ - TV], 1951,1959 1960 (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - Carleton College Sermons
      - Incl: "Law in Religion"; "Religion at Carleton"; "The Unknown God"; and "Three Ways to Judge Yourself"; "With all Thy Mind"; and "Freedom"; Dimensions of Faith"; "Things to Think About"; "Deep Can Answer Deep"; Meaning of the Messiah", 1952-1953, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 13-15)
      - Incl: "Prophecy for 1954"; "Strange Triumph"; "Holy Rollers and Scholars"; "Religion, Love and Sex"; "Is Drinking a Religious Issue?"; "Is Chapel Too Short?"; "Thus Saith the Lord"; "A Sense of Proportion" (Box 7, Folder 16-17)
      - Incl: "Religious Value of Doubt"; "Encounter with Enmity"; "Where in the World is God?"; "Investigating the Bible"; "Recovery of Wholeness in Personality"; "Signs"; "Why Call it the Book?"; "Prayer", 1955-1956 (Box 7, Folder 18-20)
    - Minnesota Sermons, 1953-1956
      - Incl: "On Doing One Thing"; "God's Family"; "Reed Shaken in the Wind"; "God at Work in Red China"; "What Kind of Peace?", 1954 (Box 8, Folder 21)
      - Incl: "Finish the Job"; "Confidence"; "To Love My Neighbor"; "Facing the Future"; "Built on the Foundation"; "Church Wedding"; "Household"; "Christ the Corner Stone"; "Success for the Church"; "Finishing What Luther Started", 1955 (Box 8, Folder 22-23)
      - Incl: "Happy New Year"; Mardi Gras Spirit"; "Lord's Prayer I & II"; "Lead Us Not into Temptation"; "Spirit in Wheels", 1956 (Box 8, Folder 24)
    - Mid-century Sermons, 1950s- 1970s
      - "Are We Ready?"; Sermon Notes; " Jesus' Hardest Saying"; "Look Inside"; Winds of God"; "God's Problems"; and "Choosing a Leader"; and "Spirit in the Wheels", 1950-1952 (Box 8, Folder 25-28)
      - Incl: "God's Family"; "Remember"; "Investigate the Churches";"The Unexpected Ways of God"; "Our Home in Nature"; and "Where Wisdom Begins"; "The Knock at the Door"; and "No Longer Strangers", 1953-1955 (Box 8, Folder 29-31)
      - Incl: "Wise Guys and Wise Men"; "Will Prayer Help?"; "No More Women"; and "In No Strange Land"; "Cross on Campus"; "Lightweight Christianity"; "In No Strange Land" [reprint], 1956-1959 (Box 9, Folder 32-35)
      - Incl: "What's all the Cheering About?"; "It is Finished"; and "Remember" [Communion Service]; "The Greeks Called Them Apostles", 1960-1963 (Box 9, Folder 36-39)
      - Incl. sermon at Mount Holyoke College; "Can Christianity Survive the World Council of Churches?"; "Christianity--Cause of Our World's Ills", 1968-1972 (Box 9, Folder 40-44)
      - Incl. "Your World of Mission"; "A Divine Extravagance"; and "Christian Faith and Global Consciousness"; "Hunger", 1974-1978 (Box 9, Folder 45-49)
    - Sermons from the 1980s
      - Incl: "Your Kingdom Come"; "A Mission for the 1980s"; and "The Missonary Reformation of the Church"; "Christian Mission Comes of Age"; "Signs of Life", 1980-1983 (Box 10, Folder 50-53)
      - Incl: "The Last War"; "Meet the Christian Family"; "Our Surprising God"; "Twenty-Five Years in God's Mission", 1984-1985 (Box 10, Folder 54-56)
      - Incl: "God in Strange Company"; "God's Project Hope"; "Christianity that Makes a Difference"; and "A Quarter Century with God: A Sermon in Celebration of Rev. and Mrs. David H. Knoebel", 1986 (Box 10, Folder 57-58)
      - Incl: "God's Project Hope"; "Come and Rejoice"; "Christ Triumph Today"; and "The Ascent of Jesus";"The General Synod Report", 1987-1989 (Box 11, Folder 59-62)
    - Sermons from the 1990s
      - Sermon Index, sermons incl. "Child at the Center" [The baptism of Elizabeth Stowe Nelson]; "Perfection"; and "Stewardship of Power", 1990-1993 (Box 11, Folder 63-67)
      - Incl: " New Year--New Covenant"; "Images of God"; "Bible Women"; and "A Working Faith in God"; "Jazz Sermon"; "Honolulu Sermon", 1994-1997 (Box 12, Folder 68-71)
      - Sermons "God Will Provide"; "Graying Gracefully to God's Glory"; "Happiness", 1998 (Box 12, Folder 72-73)
    - Chinese Christian Fellowship Sermons
      - Incl. "An Action to Remember"; "Gospel as Power"; "How to Celebrate the New Year", 1990-1998 (Box 12, Folder 74-76)
    - Miscellaneous Sermon Material
      - Children's Sermons Incl: "Goody-Goody"; "St. Paul's Son"; "Preacher's Kid"; "First Little Brother"; and "The Youth Who Lost His Coat", ca. 1950s (Box 12, Folder 77)
      - Communion Sermons Incl: "This is My Body"; "Joy is Communion"; "World Communion"; and "Eucharistic Sacrifice", 1950s (Box 12, Folder 78)
      - Misc. Worship Services/Sermons/Prayers, 1950s- 1960s (Box 13, Folder 79)
      - Misc. Worship Services/Sermons/Prayers; incl. meditations at memorial services for Alford Carleton, 1970s- 1984 (Box 13, Folder 80)
      - Sermon Seeds, notes, litanies, prayers, funeral services, 1990s, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 81-85)
  - Lectures/Talks
    - Early Lecture/Talks, 1940s